

+254720569322 jadoyo@gmail.com

Judith Ochieng

I am an experienced, committed Learning and Development expert who has a passion for effecting behavioral change in people by taking them through the learning process.

I have first class intellect with Excellent Analytical, Diagnostic, Decision making, Communication Skills and Emotional Intelligence. My nine years of experience as a Learning / Training and Development Officer has unlocked my full potential and has afforded me the acquisition of the desired knowledge, Skills and Attitudes, that has seen me not only as a key team player but also as one who has added-value in the Learning / Training and Development Section of the Human Resource Department in Kenya Civil Aviation Authority (KCAA). I am a highly educated trained and experienced professional in the area of Human Resource Management, specialized as a Learning and Development Expert. I am also a Certified ISO 9001: 2015 Lead Auditor by Kenya National Bureau of Standards

WORK EXPERIENCE

August 2019 - Present

Ag. Senior Human Capital Officer (Training & Development | KENYA CIVIL AVIATION AUTHORITY

Scope of work/ duties / responsibilities 1. Implementing training plans based on the annual training calendar 2. Organizing and monitoring all training and development activities such as Induction programmes seminars and workshops industrial attachment and exchange programmes 3. Coordinating with line managers on the identification of training needs and updating of training plans 4. Monitoring and evaluating the impact of training activities 5. Liaising with training providers / institutions Directorate of Industrial 6. Training on staff training and Industrial attachment. 7. Updating skills inventory integrated with other HR systems 8. Ensuring the training and development programs are linked to performance needs and succession plans 9. Monitoring the implementation and utilization of the departmental training budget and advising accordingly 10. Receiving and analyzing the mandatory back to work reports and liaising with respective supervisors for their implementation 11. Preparing periodic training reports 12. Facilitating knowledge sharing within the Authority Substantive Position Human Capital Officer I (T&D) Duties & Responsibilities 1. Organizing and monitoring all training and development activities such as induction programmes, seminars and workshops industrial attachment and exchange programmes. 2. Coordinating with line managers on the identification of training need updating of training plans and implementation of needs/ performance driven training programmes 3. Monitors and evaluates the impact of training and advises the Chief Training and Development officer on the results and remedial actions 4. Liaises with Training Providers / Institutions Directorate of Industrial Training on Staff Training and Industrial attachment 5. Updates skills inventory 6. Ensures the training and development programs are linked with performance needs and succession planning 7, Monitors the implementation and utilization of the departmental training budget and advises the Chief Human Capital Officer (T& D) accordingly. 8. Receives mandatory back to work reports and liaises with supervisor for their MEMBERSHIP Full Member Institute of IHRM- (Membership Number, 06023) ATTRIBUTES & HOBBIES Attributes - Results oriented, Excellent Communication and Interpersonal skills, Decisive Person with Excellent Decision Making and Problem Solving skills. Natural Ability for Maintaining and Keeping Confidentiality of Information, Ethical and values Integrity, follows laid down Rules and Procedures but also flexible and discretional. Excellent Analytical, Diagnostic and Planning skills, Proactive and independent. An excellent team player

July 2018 - Present

Ag. Senior Human Capital Officer (Training & Development | KENYA CIVIL AVIATION AUTHORITY

RESPONSIBLE FOR TRAINING & DEVELOPMENT OF ALL STAFF IN KENYA CIVIL AVIATION AUTHORITY (KCAA)

Scope of work / duties / responsibilities

- Linking KCAA's training requirements and training strategies with corporate strategies
- 2. Planning, Coordinating and overseeing all staff training and development activities such as induction programmes, seminars and workshops, industrial attachment and Internship programmes
- 3. Ensuring training and development programs are linked with performance needs and succession planning
- 4. Liaising with functional managers to develop and implement training and succession plans
- 5. Liaising with Corporate Planning and Quality Management to identify and consolidate training requirements to implement projects
- 6. Monitoring the implementation and utilization of the I training budget
- 7. Identifying credible training providers according to the regulations stipulated in Cap 237 (National Industrial Training Act)
- 8. Liaising with relevant user departments to initiate the training process
- 9. Secretariat for the Training and Development Committee

Liaising with training providers / institutions, National Industrial Training Authority on staff training and Industrial attachment

- 10. Receiving mandatory back to work reports and liaising with functional supervisors for their implementation
- 11. Maintaining and updating skills inventory
- 12. Coordinating knowledge sharing
- 13. Initiating and conducting post training impact assessments, preparing the reports and advising management on the results and remedial actions

AREAS OF ACHIEVEMENT

- 1. Successfully conducted Training Impact Assessments for all employees (800) and Prepared Reports.
- 2. Conducted Training Needs Assessment for all employees and prepared A master Training Plan for the next three years
- 3. Successfully conducted Team Building for all employees
- 4. Reviewed The Training and Development Policy and Implemented the New Policy
- 5. Reviewed the HR ISO 9001 2008 Procedures and Successfully transited them into ISO 9001 2015 Procedures
- 6. Performed Quarterly Internal ISO AUDITS
- 7. Facilitated training for all Flight Safety Inspectors (90 number) and this facilitated KCAA as the Kenya Civil Aviation regulator to get Approval from the International Civil Aviation Regulator
- (ICAO) to be granted Category 1 Status , to oversee the direct flights from Kenya to the United States of America $\,$
- 8. Formulated and implemented the Youth Apprentice/ Internship Policy
- 9. Pioneered the deployment of Interns/ apprentice to KCAA following the directive from the

Government on Youth empowerment

April 2017 - April 2019

ISO 9001:2015 INTERNAL AUDITOR | KENYA CIVIL AVIATION AUTHORITY

ISO 9001:2015 Requirements and Documentation Training PASS KEBS ISO 9001:2015 Lead auditor's Course PASS

I AM AN ISO 9001: 2015 LEAD AUDITOR

I PERFORM QUARTERLY ISO 9001: 2015 INTERNAL AUDITS IN VARIOUS DEPARTMENTS, PREPARE REPORTS ON AUDIT FINDINGS AND CONDUCT FOLLOW AUDITS TO ENSURE NON -CONFORMITIES ARE ADDRESSED.

MAIN ACHIEVEMENTS

Successfully transited ALL the KCAA ISO 9001 2008 HUMAN RESOURCE STANDARD OPERATING PROCEDURES TO ISO 9001: 2015

April 2012 - April 2012

Instructor Development Programme | KENYA CIVIL AVIATION AUTHORITY

SENSITIZING STAFF ON POLICIES AND PROCEDURES

January 2008 - March 2017

Quality Management System Internal Auditor | KENYA CIVIL AVIATION AUTHORITY

ISO 9001: 2008 Quality Management System Internal Auditor Conducting periodic internal ISO AUDITS

January 2007 - July 2009

East African School of Aviation Housekeeping /Catering Officer | KENYA CIVIL AVIATION AUTHORITY

Championed renovations of accommodation facilities that attracted and maintained full house occupancy.

January 1993 - January 2006

East African School of Aviation Housekeeping /Catering Officer II | YEAR DUTY STATION

Supervised catering for special functions and catered for large numbers of VIP'S

January 1991 - January 1992

East African School of Aviation Housekeeping /Catering Officer III | KENYA CIVIL AVIATION AUTHORITY

SUPERVISING CATERING OPERATIONS

January 1986 - January 1990

Kenya Police College Assistant Housekeeper/Cateress | OFFICE OF THE PRESIDENT

Kenya Police College Assistant House-keeper/Cateress

SUPERVISING CATERING, HOUSEKEEPING AND GENERAL HOSPITALITY OPERATIONS

EDUCATION

2013 - 2015

BSc. in HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT

MOI UNIVERSITY

SPECIALIZED IN HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT

2010 - 2011

HIGHER DIPLOMA IN HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT

INSTITUTE OF HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT

SPECIALIZED IN HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT

2008 - 2009

MASTERS OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

MOI UNIVERSITY

SPECIALIZED IN CIVIL AVIATION MANAGEMENT

1988 - 1990

HIGHER DIPLOMA IN INSTITUITIONAL MANAGEMENT, HOTEL AND CATERING OPERATIONS

KENYA POLYTECHNIC (TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF KENYA)

MANAGEMENT OF HOTEL, CATERING AND ACCOMMODATION FACILITIES

1982 - 1984

DIPLOMA IN INSTITUITIONAL MANAGEMENT

KENYA POLYTECHNIC (TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF KENYA)

MAIN SUBJECTS: CATERING: SMALL AND LARGE SCALE FOOD & BEVERAGE PRODUCTION AND SERVICE, KITCHEN HYGIENE AND FOOD POISONING, REGULATIONS GOVERNING FOOD PRODUCTION AND ACCOMMODATION PREMISES

ACCOMMODATIONS OPERATIONS, HOUSEKEEPING AND LAUNDRY, MANAGEMENT AND ACCOUNTING , FOOD COST

CONTROL, CUSTOMER SERVICE, STORES AND STORES CONTROL, CATERING FOR SPECIAL FUNCTIONS/ PEOPLE, FRONT OFFICE, FURNITURE, FITTINGS AND FURNISHINGS, ACCOMMODATION MAINTENANCE AND SERVICES

1977 - 1980

KENYA CERTIFICATE OF SECONDARY EDUCATION PANGANI GIRLS SCHOOL

SUBJECTS LEARNED: ENGLISH LANG

SUBJECTS LEARNED: ENGLISH LANGUAGE, FRENCH, SWAHILI, ENGLISH LITERATURE, MATHEMATICS, BIOLOGY, CHEMISTRY, PHYSICS, GEOGRAPHY, HISTORY

1970 - 1976

CERTIFICATE OF PRIMARY EDUCATION

Nairobi South Primary School

SUBJECTS LEARNED, ENGLISH , MATHEMATICS AND GENERAL PAPER (SCIENCE, GEOGRAPHY, HISTORY AND CIVICS)

SKILLS

- Adult education
- Assignment preparation and delivery
- Capacity planning
- · Change management
- Cleaning
- Communication
- Confidence
- Creative thinking
- Customer service
- Decision making
- Efficiency
- Empathy
- Employee evaluations
- Employee guidelines and onboarding
- · High work ethic
- Human resource and personnel development
- Integrity
- Interpersonal relationships building
- Kaizen
- Labour law
- Labour/employment law
- Meeting management
- Meeting preparation
- · Mentoring and coaching
- Motivational skills
- · Office administration, management
- Office catering
- Office tools: Word, Excel, Outlook
- Project management
- Public speaking
- Quality control and supervision
- Quality systems (ISO, CMMI, etc.)
- Regulations
- Self-awareness
- Strategizing
- Teamwork
- Training delivery
- Training event logistics
- Training program planning
- Training requirements analysis

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Luo
- English
- Swahili
- French

HOBBIES

- GETTING TO KNOW NEW PROFESSIONAL/ SOCIAL AQUAINTANCES
- LEARNING NEW CULTURES
- LEARNING NEW WAYS OF DOING THINGS
- READING
- SINGING
- TRAVELING

ASSOCIATIONS

 FULL MEMBER OF INSTITUTE OF HUMAN RESOURCE PRACTIONERS OF KENYA - TO ENHANCE PROFESSIONALISM IN HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT

CERTIFICATES

December, 2015

Human Resource Management

The HR certificate provides the foundation in human resource principles and practices demanded by employers.

April, 2019

Quality Management (ISO)

The quality management system (QMS) standard ISO 9001 provides a methodology for building, sustaining and improving quality performances.

April, 2019

Quality Management (ISO)

The quality management system (QMS) standard ISO 9001 provides a methodology for building, sustaining and improving quality performances.

May, 2016

Training of Trainers (TOT)

The TOT certification equips Trainers with the essential knowledge and pedagogy to perform effectively; as well as sharpening their skills by amalgamating them with the latest methodologies that allow them to purvey their expertise.

November, 1980

K.C.S.E

This is a certificate awarded to a candidate once they are done with their four years secondary school education programme.

February, 2019

IHRM certification

November, 1976

K.C.P.E

This is a certificate awarded to candidates after they are done with an eight year primary school programme.

November, 2000

International Computer Driving Licence (ICDL)

It is an entry level computer certification designed to demonstrate competence in computer use.

December, 2008

Human Resource Management

The HR certificate provides the foundation in human resource principles and practices demanded by employers.

December, 2009

Human Resource Management

The HR certificate provides the foundation in human resource principles and practices demanded by employers.

February, 2018

Human Resource Management

The HR certificate provides the foundation in human resource principles and practices demanded by employers.

February, 2018

Human Resource Management

The HR certificate provides the foundation in human resource principles and practices demanded by employers.

November, 2011

Human Resource Management

The HR certificate provides the foundation in human resource principles and practices demanded by employers.

August, 2012

Human Resource Management

The HR certificate provides the foundation in human resource principles and practices demanded by employers.

December, 2015

Human Resource Management

The HR certificate provides the foundation in human resource principles and practices demanded by employers.

November, 2011

Human Resource Management

The HR certificate provides the foundation in human resource principles and practices demanded by employers.

August, 2016

Human Resource Management

The HR certificate provides the foundation in human resource principles and practices demanded by employers.

February, 2015

Training of Trainers (TOT)

The TOT certification equips Trainers with the essential knowledge and pedagogy to perform effectively; as well as sharpening their skills by amalgamating them with the latest methodologies that allow them to purvey their expertise.

August, 2019

Human Resource Management

The HR certificate provides the foundation in human resource principles and practices demanded by employers.